Saeed Shakuri



Overview

I am a master's student in Data Science major at the University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran. I am truly enthusiastic about doing research at the forefront of Deep Learning methods within real-world applications in general, which leads to high-quality research in real-world challenges. I recognize the importance and my passion for this field, and I am committed to performing continuous and comprehensive research in my field of study.

Highlight of my research experience:

- I am currently working on object detection in images for my master's thesis, utilizing a method that integrates Few-Shot Learning and Vision Transformers on medical images.
- I recently collaborated on two articles titled 'Real-time facial emotion recognition in smartphones using EfficientNetV2 and quantization-aware training' which is submitted to "Journal of Real-Time Image Processing (Springer)" and 'Scalable real-time emotion recognition using EfficientNetV2 and resolution scaling.' which is published in "ICWR 10th (IEEE)".

Research interests: Machine learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Transformers

Education

University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran

M.S., Data Science

Advisor: Dr. Alireza Rezavanian

<u>Thesis:</u> Object detection with Few-Shot Learning and Vision Transformers on medical images.

Technical and Vocational University, Tehran, Iran B.E., Electronics engineering (Shamsipour college)

Project: An electronic device and a mobile application for remotely managing household keys

and monitoring environmental conditions via WiFi.

Technical and Vocational University, Karaj, Iran A.S., Electronics engineering (Beheshti College)

2016 - 2018

2018 - 2021

Publications

(<u>Published</u>) Ghadami, Omid, Alireza Rezvanian, and **Saeed Shakuri**. "Scalable Real-time Emotion Recognition using EfficientNetV2 and Resolution Scaling." 2024 10th International Conference on Web Research (ICWR). IEEE, 2024.

(Submitted) Omid Ghadami, Alireza Rezvanian, Saeed Shakuri, and Mohammad Hojjat Shamami. "Real-time facial emotion recognition in smartphones using EfficientNetV2 and quantization-aware training." In Journal of Real-Time Image Processing, Springer.

(In preparation) Saeed Shakuri, Alireza Rezvanian, "Object detection with Few-Shot Learning and Vision Transformers on medical images".

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant, Undergraduate Artificial Intelligence course

University of Science and Culture

Dr. Azadeh Tabatabaei

Teaching Assistant, Graduate Machine Learning course

University of Science and Culture

Dr. Alireza Rezvanian

Fall 2023

Fall 2022

Notable Academic Projects

Object detection with Detectron2

<u>Language</u>: Python, <u>Environment</u>: Google Colaboratory
<u>Link</u>: https://github.com/SaeedShakuri/Detectron2

Measuring sentence similarity with a TF-IDF approach

Language: Python, Environment: Google Colaboratory

Link: https://github.com/SaeedShakuri/Projects/tree/main/NLP

Using PyTorch in Deep Learning tasks (Computer Vision)

Language: Python, Environment: Google Colaboratory

Link: https://github.com/SaeedShakuri/PyTorch.git

A classification project using Ensemble Learning with the Abalone dataset

Language: Python, **Environment**: Google Colaboratory

Link: https://github.com/SaeedShakuri/Projects/tree/main/Ensemble%20Learning

An Image classification project using Transfer Learning with ResNet50

Language: Python, Environment: Google Colaboratory

Link: https://github.com/SaeedShakuri/Projects/tree/main/Convolutional-Neural-Network/Transfer%20Learning

Professional Services

Reviewer

Wiley - The Journal of Engineering Aug. 2023

Elsevier - Data in Brief Journal

Mar. 2023 - Apr. 2023 Jul. 2023 & Jan. 2024

University of Science and Culture

· Conducting assessments of computer science bachelor students' final projects, followed by assigning grades

Presenter Dec. 2022

University of Science and Culture

• Presentation title: An Introduction to Few-Shot Learning

Work Experience

BlazingFallApps, remotely

Mar. 2020 - Nov. 2021

Software Developer

• Developing various mobile applications with the Flutter framework

PergasTeb, remotely

May. 2020 - Oct. 2020

Software Developer

• Developing a medical android application with the Flutter framework

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, Dart, C

Softwares and Tools

Google Colaboratory, EndNote, LaTex, MiniTab, VSCode, Android Studio

Technological Proficiencies

PyTorch, Detectron2, OpenCV, NumPy, Matplotlib, Flutter

IELTS Academic (Taken in Sep. 2023)

Overall: 7, Speaking: 7.5, Listening: 7, Writing: 6.5, Reading: 7

Masters Courses

11.000.0 Courses	
Natural Language Processing GPA: 4	Spring 2023
Computer Vision GPA: 3.93	Fall 2022
Computational social network GPA: 3.73	Fall 2022
Artificial Neural Networks GPA: 3.97	Spring 2022
Machine Learning	Spring 2022
GPA: 3.91 Seminar GPA: 3.8	Spring 2022
Data Science Mathematics GPA: 4	Fall 2021
Advanced Algorithms GPA: 3.73	Fall 2021
Applied Data Analysis GPA: 3.76	Fall 2021

References

References available upon request.